MICHAEL SAMARA

3100 BARTON POINT DRIVE AUSTIN, TX 78733 · (737) 701-0185 · MICHAELSAM08@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY

Michael is a creative and dependable Junior Web Developer. Broadly knowledgeable in React, JavaScript, CSS and HTML as well as the principles and techniques of website construction and maintenance. An effective process-driven student and teacher who creates and implements training for businesses and students. Collaborative team player with the ability to effectively communicate at all organizational and education levels. Exceptional problem solving skills, strong business judgement, and demonstrated experience leading cross-functional teams.

CORE TECHNICAL SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Problem solving
- Process improvement
- JavaScript
- React

- CSS
- HTML
- Data visualization
- Instructional design and training

EXPERIENCE

AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY

Student

Austin, TX January 2018-Present

- Front end development: React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Familiarity with Slack and Github for collaboration

TEACHING ABROAD AND VIRTUAL CLASSROOM

China & Colombia 2016-Present

Roles: ESL Instructor, English Teacher

- Researched and designed development plans for adult students learning Business English
- Utilizing technology, developed interactive lessons enabling students to understand and use English both inside the classroom and in their daily lives
- Created daily lesson plans, materials, and assessments to develop ESL central areas: grammar syntax, listening, reading, speaking, vocabulary and writing
- Participated in planning and training sessions for classroom technology integration
- Generated syllabi and taught classes to students planning to matriculate to a U.S. college/university

GROWTHTROOP

Barranquilla, Colombia

2016-2017

DIRECTOR NORTH AMERICAN SALES

- Hired sales teams responsible for North American distribution of services
- Facilitated and coordinated communication between sales team, engineers and designers in multicultural/bilingual environment

USAA

San Antonio, TX 2007-2015

INVESTMENT COMPLIANCE MANAGER

Previous Roles: Sales Manager, Relationship Manager

- Performed data analysis to identify trends, create, and implement plans to meet organizational objectives.
- Built multi-generational relationships with members through various communication and marketing channels
- Delivered solutions to that meet individual members' financial needs
- Coached teams of financial advisors to maximize sales potential and relationship reinforcement with clients.

 Built collaborative relationships with business partners across the enterprise to create line of sight for financial advisors and leaders.

CITI-SMITH BARNEY
FINANCIAL ADVISOR, PRODUCT MANAGEMENT
Boston, MA
2003 - 2007

 Performed product research, comparison, and change implementation with vendors for annuity and publicly traded equity investments with a \$150 MM client-base.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY
Full Stack Software Engineering
competencies in JavaScript, HTML and CSS

BS, CLARK UNIVERSITY Business Management 2003

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS & ORGANIZATIONS

- TEFL (certified to Teach English as a Foreign Language)
- TOEIC (Test of English for International Communication)
- Chartered Retirement Planning Counselor
- Completed all Certified Financial Planner modules
- FINRA Series 24, 7, and 66